all right hello I just realized I did
not lock my door my five-year-old is
home because I'm doing this before I
drop her off the daycare because I have
to do after I drop her off at daycare
like on your doctor's and get my hair
cut I help finally get this all figured
out um how's happy my coffee this
morning and I count the Venn diagram
could I wanted to show people I was
gonna rewrite it and do it under on a
white board and then said I I'm actually
just gonna rewrite it so I'm right here
it's a little messy and I would like to
though I don't have a pen so let me stir
write things
okay so this is the Venn diagram it is
the words Julie words use your words
when something needs to get done when
there's a task that needs to get done
there's a certain thing that needs to
happen before that task is done and that
is someone who is going to perform the
task needs to have these things three
things they need to know that the task
needs to be performed right knowledge of
the problem of knowledge that this thing
needs to get done a lot of times that
comes from your boss your job
description right like oh these things
need to get done then they need to have
the ability to do the task the knowledge
is like the knowledge just a skill set
to do the task as well as within their
parameters of limitations that there
have enough time to do it that they have
the the health ability to do it that
they're you know not stressed out with
everything else in life like if that
everything amalgamated they have the
ability to do it the last piece of this
Venn diagram is that they have the
motivation to do it and in a job I mean
the current capitalist system that
motivation is generally seen as money
and only money like money is the only
motivating factor any of us would never
work for which we know isn't true but
it's like if we stop with money
everyone's lazy and no one's motivated
and I don't I don't think that's true
either at all but the beauty of the
system that we're creating is we're
actually starting with a culture of
people that are
motivated only internally only within
because we're not paying you so if you
want to come and cooperate and create a
better world that's the people who are
gonna come in the beginning and so what
I want to talk about is so those three
pieces have to be there right the
knowledge of this task needs to get done
the ability to do the task and the
motivation to do the task all in the
same individual so you might see a
pothole on the street you have the
knowledge it's there you don't have the
ability on motivation to do it so you
call the city and the city sends
somebody with the ability and the
motivation I either day May so we're
gonna help with that knowledge piece by
like reporting up those things right
that like anyone can see the pothole in
the system anyone can see anything and
it gets it's gets bored enough once we
know there's a problem well how
important does it because if there's
like a million potholes which one do we
start with maybe the one outside of
hospitals maybe right like where do it
where do we start so we're helping with
that by reporting and funneling so both
like in the beginning when we don't have
technology and such a place it's kinda
just me it becomes like hey I need help
with this and so it's like goes out to
everyone I you nobody at the moment and
and then as we create the technology can
go to okay Patil needs fixing this is a
bad example because we're not fixing
potholes so later later much later in
the program because cities fix potholes
as long as their cities if we haven't
disrupted that yet we don't need to fix
potholes theoretically I mean I know
Domino is fixing potholes maybe we fix
those ones but anyway that it goes out
to the people know how to do that right
it's like hey I need I need help with
with choreography in this the scene and
it goes out to people who have the
ability to choreograph to have said yes
I want to and and they still might they
have the ability they might have the
motivation for your project right so
then you might have to pay someone if
it's not a grandiose enough project that
like if you're telling your grandparents
story may be enough people don't care
about that to do it for an internal
motivation and you might have to pay for
it right so it's starting with the
internal motivation and ugly
do you really truly want to do this
because there's so much power and beauty
there versus like yeah I guess I'll do
and if you pay me right like that's just
already the motivation in them itself
for paying people is already hindering
getting that Venn diagram done it's like
okay how motivated you have to be in
order if you're only gonna do it for pay
and you wouldn't do it if you were doing
it for free
and we're hoping with getting people the
knowledge of the task the right people
which is all about like for me of
marketing you come to the solution it's
like getting marketing to everyone is a
little broken marketing to the people
that you want to market to who you've
created the solution for is brilliant
but we don't have trust in that system
anymore it's like yeah okay you say this
is gonna help me but I don't really
believe it the ability piece were
starting with where we're starting so
anyone involved it's like oh he who has
the best of this ability right like in
post-apocalyptic shows that I maybe
watch um they have like there's no more
doctors right or like there's one doctor
so it's like a nurse ends up performing
like bullet hole surgery right because
they're the best person there to do it
and that becomes what what we're
creating right that like okay maybe you
barely know Excel spreadsheet but we
need an Excel spreadsheet on here the
best with the motivation to do it so
yeah jump on board we understand it's
not gonna be perfect it's gonna be
better than nothing right so and as that
that gains were also with like further
phase is gonna be helping people reduce
their stress in their overall life by
creating technology that helps do that
right like oh this technology helps me
eat better this technology helps you
find my day better I'll see him to
Project Manager and better so it's
distressing people flies by asking them
where is the stress how do we help right
like where is everyone's stress I and
also sore freeing up like their time and
their their ability and we're teaching
them so part of what somebody's you know
thing that needs to get done their
ability motivation is gonna be to teach
the new new people that don't have the
skillset they're right really so it's
both like okay who's
at least barely capable of this and
wants to learn more who is amazing at
this and wants to write like it kind of
observers who want to kind of go down
that that looks like who's who's a
doctor in charge of the bullet wounds
and like oh you worked in combat zones
you're great but we don't have that one
okay you're the Bradys no Jan yachts it
looks like all right surgery in general
it's like okay other just a GP no no
actually I think I'd rather have a nurse
take my boat window then bit a GP just
like a nurse who worked at your let's
say yeah that's just hierarchy and such
but that we are both like we're gonna
help people with their ability by
teaching people by like we need more
people to have that ability to be able
to have it the other piece is motivation
we're starting with free right so things
that are super easy for anyone to do
like basically anyone has the ability to
do and we have the knowledge because
someone said hey we need this data set
like we need every product in the world
and put it into the computer okay that's
that's a task that's a big task but
somebody's task is to break that down
right we don't have to is the product on
the Shelf is it included in the database
then we need it okay that's like okay if
anyone could have the ability cuz it's
super easy and you just take a picture
of it and then it's in the database
right it takes the name with the logo
take a picture of the ingredients and it
it puts all of that information great if
it needs to be broken down further or
someone takes a picture and someone else
does the data in folks we don't have
that technology yet that can is like
every single little task is its own med
diagram so that we need every product
everywhere it's like it's one it's like
well I don't have no one has the ability
to import all of them but the ability to
break it down into the crowd and putting
it is possibly the word tasks then
having if no one's doing it they're like
actually that's not him enough of
motivating factor right we don't make
people wrong like we haven't motivated
them enough so now we gamify it right
now it's like okay what if you get
points for how many things you you
inputted it what if it's like Pokemon go
with all the pokemons so maybe less
popular but where if someone calls it
like you know like hey what's this price
at and the first person to get it
that's that gets the point so whatever
it happens to be that we can apply it to
increase the motivation not okay now
we're going to start paying people
because that model doesn't work if you
pay people right it might work you're
capable fractions of a cent but are you
going to go out and take a picture of
like a million things to get ten bucks I
don't I don't think so
I think we're more likely to do it for a
game of ID system so dealing with the
Venn diagram of you can see it's like I
can't even read this upside down
knowledge that the task needs to get
done ability to do the task and the
motivation from internal motivation of
external and as you keep going it's
going to cost you more and more money
right like once you get to the external
motivation doesn't mean it has to be
money external motivation can be like
prestige right that I get to say that I
helped create this that I get to say it
can be just like I get to feel I get to
know that I know it's great those that's
internal external of like the world gets
to know that I created this is still an
external one but it's not money and it's
it's not gonna cost us any more it's
like sure you have a sticker you can
have the rights to say that you you
created this you don't get the rights to
own it the lights you created it so
that's how we're saving the world is by
breaking down tasks into bite-sized
chunks and being able to I mean this
isn't I know ice is like Venn diagram to
save the world this is it this is part
of the bigger global cooperative but
like how we save the world with
cooperation through technology and a big
piece of it is this right like right now
it's me this is the technology it's me
it's like hey I need and right now I'm
trying to figure out how to communicate
the idea so I need people to help me
possibly get the idea that's the if
you're watching this you've just heard
the knowledge of the task that I mean if
you have the ability to do that and I
have people kind people contacting you
have the ability they might not have the
motivation to do this whining because
unfortunately in that subject the
ability to write they don't necessarily
have the ability to understand what I'm
trying to say at the level I'm trying to
say it right like I'm not good enough
yet to communicate it to everyone that's
why I need someone who both to
understand this idea and communicate it
to everyone and that ability is maybe
not there and yet I do have people who
are jumping on who are like yes but I
can write so I like I will do it to the
best
ability and that's awesome an amazing it
and the motivating factor I very much
how perfect the time of course single
mom who doesn't have money to motivate
people to do these things because it
means that people have to do it for food
items have to do it for breathing you
have to do it for free but like that's
my only option so that's perfect project
so often like I only want people working
on this project that would do it for
free like I I'm hopefully gonna be able
to create a job for myself out of this
I'm not on disability anymore eventually
down the road but if that never happens
I'm not doing this for that I'm doing
this to create this in the world because
it's my internal motivating factor to
like live my purpose and it's amazing
and I think here I can't come so I'm
going to end this by